bigpond.com 2001-12-04

# Telstra Privacy Statement

**Privacy**  
Telstra is committed to the protection of your personal information. Telstra's business is governed by the Telecommunications Act of 1997, Industry Codes of Practice and Telstra's own policies and procedures. This includes [Telstra’s Privacy Protection Principles](http://www.telstra.com.au/privacy/docs/0855ppol.pdf) which have been designed to ensure that personal information is protected. 

Our Privacy Statement contains the following important information regarding your use of the telstra.com web site: 

Collection of your personal information  
How we use your personal information  
Disclosure of your information  
Security of your information  
How to access, correct or update your information  
Children's privacy  
What else you should know about Privacy  
How to contact us  

When you visit the telstra.com web site, you are encouraged to read the information provided on the Telstra sites you are using. This includes certain services offered (such as BigPond Internet access) which may have separate terms of use and privacy information. 

The telstra.com web site consists of many pages and services. These are offered on our three main web addresses (known as ‘domains’) - telstra.com, bigpond.com and telstra.com.au. Information provided may be subject to change from time to time so we encourage you to check our online Privacy policies and this Privacy Statement regularly. 

For further detailed Privacy information, including Telstra’s Corporate Procedures, please refer to the Telstra [Privacy Policy](http://www.telstra.com.au/privacy/). 

If you have any concerns or questions, please contact Telstra by phoning FREECALL™ 1 800 266 000* or use the [Contact Us](http://www.telstra.com.au/contact/email.cfm?page=22) page to send your questions and comments via email. To refer to telstra.com’s Terms of Use, please click here. 

**Collection of your personal information**  
When you provide Telstra with your personal information via the telstra.com web site, we will inform you of how the information will be used. We value your trust in the telstra.com web site. In all cases, your information will be held in strict confidence. 

The types of personal information that we collect from you will depend on how you use the telstra.com web site. For example, when applying for telstra.com membership we will collect details such as your name, email address, age, gender, and some details of your personal interests, your preferences for receiving commercial email and receiving market research surveys via email. Some of this information is essential for us to be able to accurately identify who is using the service and as such is mandatory. 

Other types of information are collected to help us profile who is using the services and what their interests are. Information of this type is often optional - you need only fill it in if you wish to do so. For example, you will have the option to provide details of your Internet usage and your BigPond username and password. 

telstra.com records other information as well. This information is used to improve the structure and performance of telstra.com to provide the user with an improved service. Whenever a page is requested from our web server, Telstra records the time, date and URL of the request, along with information on the browser software that is being used. We also anonymously track the pattern of visitor usage across telstra.com web sites. Telstra will do this by issuing an anonymous user ID. This anonymous ID uses a feature in your web browser called a Cookie. This cookie identifies and recognises the computer (but not the person using the computer) when you visit telstra.com web sites. 

Cookies are pieces of information that a website can transfer to an individual's computer hard drive for record keeping. Cookies can make using telstra.com easier by storing information about your preferences on a particular website. This will enable you to take full advantage of the services that telstra.com offers. The use of cookies is an industry standard and you'll find most major websites use them. Most Internet browsers are pre-set to accept cookies. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can adjust your Internet browser to disable cookies or to warn you when cookies are being used. 

Telstra use [DoubleClick](http://www2.doubleclick.net/au/) to supply ad-serving services for the telstra.com web site. DoubleClick uses cookies for anonymous profiling of users to tailor advertising to user preferences. No personally identifiable information is collected by DoubleClick from the telstra.com web site. If you wish to opt-out of anonymous profiling performed by DoubleClick, please indicate this preference at the DoubleClick web site by clicking [here](http://www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy/privacy/ad-cookie/default.asp?asp_object_1=&)

telstra.com web sites utilise [Red Sheriff](http://www.redsheriff.com/) RedMeasure to measure web site performance. Information collected is aggregated for reporting purposes. No personally identifiable information is collected by this service. The use of the Red Sheriff service assists Telstra in measuring and improving the structure and ease of use of our web sites. 

We will not collect any personal information from you revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, or details of health, disability or sexual activity or orientation. Exceptions to this include: 

  * where you have given express consent to Telstra to do so; 
  * where there are reasonable grounds to believe that disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life or health; 
  * the use is authorised by law or reasonably necessary to enforce the law; or 
  * when the information is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim. 

**How we use your personal information**  
The personal information that you provide to Telstra during registration for products and services on telstra.com is used for identification purposes and will assist you to subscribe to telstra.com services more easily. The information we gather from your use of the telstra.com web site enables us to provide better-personalised services that are tailored to your needs. Recording usage patterns helps us to identify the areas of our site that are popular and those that are not. By using cookies, users can specify their unique preferences. 

Telstra aggregates the data that is gathered when you use telstra.com for analysis purposes. Personally identifiable characteristics are removed and the user remains anonymous, unless you have given prior specific consent for Telstra to recognise your usage. Additional data provided to us is used to examine Internet trends and demographics to help Telstra offer you improved online products and services. We may use this personal information or data for a purpose other than these purposes (specified above) if : 

  * you would reasonably expect us to use the personal information for that other purpose; and 
  * that other purpose is related to these purposes (specified above). For example, sending you emails providing essential information about your Telstra online service. 

Telstra may also use your personal information for the purpose of direct marketing. We may only use your personal information or data for the purpose of direct marketing in relation to promotional activities where it is impracticable for us to obtain your prior express consent. However, when Telstra does this, we will provide an express opportunity when we first contact you to decline receiving any further marketing communications from Telstra, via an opt-out mechanism. Telstra will only send emails to you if you have elected to receive such emails or if they are in response to an email we have received from you. 

You may also notify us at any time that you do not want to receive any marketing communications from Telstra by phoning FREECALL™ 1 800 266 000* or by using the [Contact Us](http://www.telstra.com.au/contact/email.cfm?page=22) page to send your request via email. 

If we wish to use any of this personal information, information or data for any purpose other than those specified above, we will not do so unless we have your express consent to do so. 

Exceptions to this include: 

  * where there are reasonable grounds to believe that disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life or health; 
  * where Telstra suspects that unlawful activity is or has been engaged in and uses the personal information, information or data to investigate the suspected unlawful activity; or 
  * the use is authorised by law or reasonably necessary to enforce the law. These uses may include where Telstra is required to provide information in response to subpoenas or warrants or other legal processes including requests from the Australian Stock Exchange. 

**Disclosure of your information**  
The information we collect from you is strictly confidential. Telstra will not reveal, disclose, sell, distribute, rent, licence, share or pass that information on to any third parties, other than those who are contracted to Telstra to keep the information confidential or are subject to a statute or binding scheme which imposes similar restrictions to Telstra’s [Privacy Protection Principles](http://www.telstra.com.au/privacy/docs/0855ppol.pdf) regarding the handling of personal information. 

We may disclose the personal information, other information or data we collect from you for the purpose specified to you at the time of collection or for another purpose if: 

  * you would reasonably expect us to disclose it for that purpose; and 
  * that purpose is related to the purpose specified to you at the time of collection. 

If we wish to disclose any of this personal information, information or data other than as set out above, we will not do so unless we have your express consent to do so. We will not provide your email address to third parties without your consent. 

Exceptions to this include: 

  * where there are reasonable grounds to believe that disclosure is necessary to prevent a threat to life or health; 
  * where Telstra suspects that unlawful activity is or has been engaged in and uses the personal information, information or data to investigate the suspected unlawful activity; or, 
  * the use is authorised by law or reasonably necessary to enforce the law. These uses may include where Telstra is required to provide information in response to subpoenas or warrants or other legal process including requests from the Australian Stock Exchange. 

**Security of your information that you may send to or receive from using telstra.com**  
We will take reasonable steps to ensure that all information we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete, up-to-date and stored in a secure environment accessed only by authorised persons. Transmissions sent to or from telstra.com are routinely monitored for quality control and systems administration. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While we strive to protect your personal information from misuse, loss and unauthorised access, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us or receive from our online products or services. These activities are conducted at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security. 

Credit card information is among the most sensitive and important data that telstra.com collects. Telstra operates secure servers to minimise the risk of unauthorised use of such information. Credit card information that is transmitted via our secure servers is encrypted in accordance with the highest standards over the proven EFTPOS network. For obvious reasons, please do not send credit card information through unsecured electronic mail. 

**How to access, correct or update your information**  
You will always have access to the information and content that you provide to us. You can easily edit or delete your personal information provided during registration to telstra.com by clicking here, unless it is mandatory information required for your membership application. You will need your username and password to access and modify your registration information. 

If you wish to access or modify personal information which you have provided via a Telstra website but you cannot access the information at the site mentioned above, please send an email using the [Contact Us](http://www.telstra.com.au/contact/email.cfm?page=22) page. 

Exceptions to this include: 

  * where providing access will pose a serious threat to life or health of any individual or pose an unreasonable impact on the privacy of an individual; 
  * your request for access is frivolous or vexatious; 
  * where the information relates to existing legal proceedings between Telstra and you and the information would not be discoverable in the process of those legal proceedings; or 
  * where providing access would be unlawful, may prejudice an investigation of possible unlawful activity, may prejudice enforcement of laws, or denying access is specifically authorised by law. 

If Telstra does not allow you to access your personal information, we will provide you with the reasons for our decision. If you believe that the personal information we collect, use or disclose is inaccurate, incomplete or not up to date but Telstra does not agree with you, we will post a statement of your claim where that information is kept and accessed. 

**Children's privacy**  
The safety of children is very important to us. 

We ask that children under the age of 18 have a parent or guardian verify their membership application with telstra.com. Whilst telstra.com will make every reasonable effort to ensure that children's privacy and other rights are not compromised, it is ultimately the responsibility of parents to monitor their children's Internet usage. 

**What else you should know about privacy**  
Remember to close your browser when you have finished your user session. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. You as an individual are responsible for the security of and access to your own computer. 

Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information over the Internet (for example: in discussion forums, via email, or in chat sites) that this information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information in publicly accessible online forums, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your username and passwords and any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are using the Internet and telstra.com. 

For further Privacy information, please refer to The [Australian Privacy Commissioner’s Web Site](http://www.privacy.gov.au/). 

**How to contact us**  
If you have any concerns or questions, please contact Telstra by phoning FREECALL™ 1 800 266 000* or use the [Contact Us](http://www.telstra.com.au/contact/email.cfm?page=22) page to send your questions and comments via email. 

Thank you for taking the time to read the telstra.com Privacy Statement. 

TM Trademark of Telstra Corporation Limited. ACN 051 775 556, ABN 33 051 775 556 

*** A free call from a fixed phone.**

 ****
